Arna Bontemps Papers
Arna Bontemps Papers
- Writings
  - Miscellaneous
    - "The Sunny Side of the Street / by L.H. & N.J., submitted by Arna Bontemps", story outline; character sketches (Box 74)
      See also Correspondence-Subject Files: Huntley, Leston.
    - "The Symbols of Despair" [book on origins of racism], outline only (Box 74)
    - "Tom-Tom Treasure" [juvenile], typescript manuscript; 6 folders (Box 75)
    - "Yielding Seed" [novel], typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 75)
    - "Young King Cole: a Boy Who Earned a Fortune" [biography] (Box 75, 76)
      See also Correspondence-Subject Files: Cole, Robert A.
      manuscript notes
      Typescript manuscript (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous project proposals, synopses (Box 76)
    - Miscellaneous notes, manuscript fragments (Box 76)
- Memorabilia
  - Addresses and address lists, business cards, telephone numbers, etc. (Box 77)
  - Audiorecordings
    - Iinterview with Arna Bontemps at Yale University by Margaret Perry, Education Librarian, University of Rochester, 1970; bontemps_001; bontemps_002; 2 audiocassettes (Box 77)
    - "Arna Bontemps - Portrait" (WDCN-TV, June 17th), 1973; bontemps_003 (Box 77)
  - Awards, citations (Box 77)
  - Course outlines, notes, bibliographies (Box 77)
  - Criticism and interpretation, 1939-1997 (Box 77)
  - Family-related (Box 77)
  - Financial
    - Credit cards and related material (Box 77)
    - Insurance, health (Box 77)
    - Insurance, life (Box 77)
    - Leases and housing-related material (Box 77)
    - Pension reports (Box 77)
    - Receipts (Box 77)
  - Lecture itineraries, travel connections (Box 77)
  - Photographs (Box 77)
  - Printed material
    - Clippings
      - about Bontemps, 1930-1940s; 2 folders (Box 77)
      - about Bontemps, 1950-1960s; undated; 4 folders (Box 78)
      - Obituaries and tributes, 1973-1974; 2002 (Box 78)
      - "St. Louis Woman" / "Blues Opera" / "Free and Easy", 1945-1960; undated (Box 78)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
    - Programs for "St Louis Woman," various productions (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
  - Research materials
    - Africa (Box 82, 83)
      Consists of printed material collected, in part, in connection with trip to East Africa, presumably as background for proposed "New Africa Series," for which Bontemps was to have been editor
    - Civil rights in the U.S., printed materials (Box 84)
    - Time line on note cards of important historical dates (Box 84)
    - Langston Hughes (Box 85)
      Assembled by Bontemps for biography of Langston Hughes, this material contains photocopies of correspondence from Yale University Library (?) with Bontemps, Walter Brough, Sylvia Chen, Countee Cullen, Ralph Ellison, Ezra Pound, Wallace Thurman, and Langston Hughes' father.
  - Reviews
    - American Negro Poetry (Box 78)
    - American Negro Reference Book / edited by John P. Davis (Box 78)
    - American Negro Short Stories / edited by John Henrik Clarke (Box 78)
    - Anger and Beyond / edited by Herbert Hill (Box 78)
    - Anyplace But Here (Box 78)
    - Black Thunder (Box 78)
    - The Book of Negro Folklore (Box 79)
    - The Book of Negro Humor / selected and edited by Langston Hughes (Box 79)
    - Chariot in the Sky (Box 79)
    - Drums at Dusk (Box 79)
    - Famous American Negro Poets / by Charlemae Rollins (Box 79)
    - Famous Negro Athletes (Box 79)
    - The Fast Sooner Hound (Box 79)
    - Father of the Blues / by W.C. Handy (with the assistance of Arna Bontemps) (Box 79)
    - Frederick Douglass: Slave, Fighter, Freeman (Box 79)
    - God Sends Sunday (Box 79)
    - Golden Slippers (Box 79)
    - Hold Fast to Dreams (Box 79)
    - Lonesome Boy (Box 79)
    - The Old South: "A Summer Tragedy" and Other Stories of the Thirties (Box 79)
    - 100 Years of Negro Freedom (Box 79)
    - Personals (Box 79)
    - The Poetry of the Negro (Box 79)
    - Popo and Fifina (Box 79)
    - Sad-Faced Boy (Box 79)
    - "St. Louis Woman" (Box 79)
    - Sam Patch, the High, Wide, & Handsome Jumper (Box 79)
    - Slappy Hooper, the Wonderful Sign Painter (Box 79)
    - The South Today / edited by Willie Morris (Box 79)
    - The Story of George Washington Carver (Box 79)
    - Story of the Negro (Box 79)
    - They Seek a City (Box 80)
    - We Have Tomorrow (Box 80)
    - You Can't Pet a Possum (Box 80)
  - Travel-related material, guidebooks, Berlitz phrase books, etc.
    - England (Box 80)
    - France (Box 80)
    - Haiti (Box 80)
    - Italy (Box 80)
    - Uganda (Box 81)
    - Yugoslavia, 2 folders (Box 81)
    - General, 2 folders (Box 81)
  - Voter registration cards for Arna and Alberta Bontemps, 1955 (Box 81)
  - Writings by others
    - Dramatization by unknown author of "Wings on His Shoulders," from We Have Tomorrow (Box 81)